Hey guys, welcome to another tactics discovery.
So this is one of important things, so once you get on to the organization in any of
a mission, let us think there is a thousand mission in the organization and if I compromise
one of the server and you need to move from one mission to another because hijacking or
hacking one mission is not a very big bill, it's not really helpful for any of them.
If you think about any of an attacker, if you compromised any one mission in the organization,
this will be, this is not a helpful thing because they will be easily rebuilding the
database, the device only contain a few of sensitive data, so only you can hijack few things.
But what, what if you had thousand mission in the organization, you had all the, all the
missions inside the organization.
So now the internal employees of the organization, they cannot able to access their mission
and all the mission sensitive data get published in any of dark over cloud platforms.
So this, this will be a very big deal to the organization because they need to pay a lot
of money to erase the data, right.
So once you achieved the differentization tactics in any of the mission, you will be
going for, for a next tactics like discovery, maybe mitral will be also showing the same,
let's jump on to the mitral here, so once we, once you've done everything, we already
did a credential access to information and all and once you, once you have a credential
access, you will be getting a lot of credentials, I already said maybe you will be getting
active directory credentials, lot of RDP uses credential, excuse me, human passwords.
So the next, next tactics will be jumping on to the discovery section, so you will be
understanding what is the internal network infrastructure, you will be understanding how
the network was architected and how the network was structured inside the organizations
and who are all the RDP uses, who are all the, what are the machines surrounding and
what is the gateway information and what are the service was there, ID was there, each
and everything and domains are there, whether the domain has any trust or not, each
and everything will be getting from the discovery tactics, okay.
Because the next, next tactics, you will be jumping, we will be moving on to the lateral
movement, so the lateral movement is nothing but you will be jumping from one machine
to one another.
So I already said the organization have 1000 machine, you compromise 20 and you need
to jump on to other 999 machine, so you will be scanning the internal networks and you
will be understanding the networks, how it was structured and you will be start taking
the lateral movement tactics, right.
So this is the flow and this is the path for the next cybersecurity attacks we are going
to follow, even the attackers will be following this, okay.
So there is a lot of tool to scan the internal networks as we already know, there will
be advanced IP scan or angry IP scan on its scan and few scanning tools, but if you install
this scanning tool inside the, any of the machine, so sometime your EDRs or antivirus software
will be cache-up and it will be detected and it will be given a lot to the analyst who
is working, okay.
So but we can also take information from the normal command room, we will not get as much
information but we can gather some of the information, like we can ping whatever host
which has I have, let me ping for 18.1, so I am already, I am getting a request so I can
assume the 18.1 was online and if I give the ARP-A, you can understand few of the host,
it was giving an ARP request, like one dot one dot 2981 to 65 and few of the host and
let me ping for ARP-A 192.168.18.1, so here you can find the physical
address of my gateway, once you get the physical address, you can, if you need you can
go for a max checker, so you will be getting, you will be getting, get an extra information
about what the, what router I was using and this information, I was using the how, how
how I take technologies, how I write router, so from the MAC address you can find what
was the device, so that's Dell or HD or Apple machines or any, any others, you can also
find the VPN, VPN name, VPN vendor name, firewall vendors name, etc, okay, so this is
enough, the thing, and you can also use the in the based commands to be domain, so what
are the, what are the domain information, like visible computers inside the domain, so
as of now I do not have an, I do not have an active directory that was configured in my
machine, so I will not get much information here, so, because it was saying system error
6 chronometer has been observed, the list of server follow, blue is not currently available
because I didn't configure the domain in my visual environment, that way it was showing,
so next command we can do ipconfig slash all to list each and every information about
the device, and we have other commands as well, we have an account discovery command
like net user to list all the user, so here we can see the administrator attacker, guest
user, and the user, we have, we have plenty of thing, and let's, again, numerate the local
group, so here you can find few of the list, few of the local group it has listed, access
control assistant operator administrator list, and we have a remote desktop user, so here
you can find of let me check for net unit local group remote desktop, this is, okay.
So, there is a, there is no more users was present inside the remote desktop group, let
me check for an administrator group, so here you can find few users, they are in
administrator, administrator level group, so administrator, attacker, and user, these three
users are in the administrator, so you can understand how the network has been structured
and who are all the domain group, who are all this domain group, and whether they have
an RDP, they can use an RDP or not, whether they are in the administrator group or each
and everything, so let me show another command, "OMI slash", this is one of the common
command that was used by threat actors to check the privilege of an account, so this
is an administrator account, so that we are getting high mandatory level, we have already
seen a lot of things in a privilege escalation section about escalating the privileges,
and so once you get some of the account and domain-based information, so the next step
of the threat actors, they will be jumping on to the system-based information, you can
use system info command to load the system information, so what are the hard fit studies,
and whether the which update we are in, and macro, etc, etc, so what are the physical
memory, and everything, it will be giving, so you can see here, so you will be getting
each and every information about my, about the mission, so what was the processor, what
was the hard fixers, and the memory space, everything will be getting from this, okay, and
you can also get much information using the login tool, the WMIC, computer system,
you get name, domain, manufacturer, so here you can see it given few of the information,
no text, you can see the machine, let me show my screen on from, so here you can find my machine
information, so I do not have any kind of domain, so it was not given any domain, and it was
given other things like model, manufacturer, and fewer information, so you can get a lot
of information from the machine using the pre different custom commands of the logins,
so this is one of the best, best example of how the threat tactics use the commands
to enumerate from the machine, the reason I am showing these commands, because when you
are in a blue teaming, so if you started investigating the threat tactics activity, if you
doing some foreign 16, any of the machine, so you need to understand this, all the commands
are used for the discovery to get the account information, okay, account information, network
information, and domain information, so you can easily figure it out, what was happening
inside the machine, and what are the commands get executed, so if you think of, you think
about the PowerShell, so there is a powerful commands get AD users, so it will give the user
information in the Active Directory, so now we do not have an Active Directory that
it configured, so we will not get anything, and we have other powerful commands also, NetIP
can find a few information from here, if the Active Directory has been configured, it will
show plenty of information about the machines and about the users, but our test environment
we do not have an Active Directory, but this is not like an organization, because organization
have an Active Directory that has been configured internally, so you will be get much, much
information, then what we are getting here, okay, so that's all about the video, and
these are the few enumeration discovery commands that the threat tactics may use to get
information about internal networks, users, domain and about these systems, okay, so let's
swap off from here, and we will connect you guys in the next video, see you, bye bye.